<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<data>
	<cards>
		<element>
			<name>Hexapod</name>
			<description>
				A six legged robot. The device is remotely controlled via bluetooth. This is an ongoing project with a goal to design a bot that can walk up stairs and carry an object.
			</description>
			<image>
				hexapod_card.png
			</image>
		</element>
		<element>
			<name>NES Controller</name>
			<description>
				A group project for a digital logic design course. The aim of the project was to design a system on an FPGA that would be able to convert signals from various controllers to a NES console.
			</description>
			<image>
				nes_card.png
			</image>
		</element>
		<element>
			<name>Drones</name>
			<description>
				Multiple different drones created for the purpose of racing. The common goal is to make a multi-rotored that can fly as fast as possible.
			</description>
			<image>
				drone_card.png
			</image>
		</element>
	</cards>
	<pages>
		<element>
			<name>Hexapod</name>
			<column>
				<image>hexapod_1.png</image>
				<text>
					The hexapod features 18 servos that move six legs to make the bot crawl in all directions. To communicate with servos an SAMD21 MCU device communicates via I2C to a PCA9625W. The movement of the legs is similarly modeled to that of an Ant.
				</text>
			</column>
				<video>hexapod_2.mp4</video>
				<text>
					This project was inspired with the intent to make a bot that could walk on almost all terrains. This includes terrains with obstacles and debris. At its current configuration it is not quite set up for this. Two cameras will be added and possibly another processor to evaluate and pick up its visual surroundings. 
				</text>
			<column>
			</column>
			<column>
				<image>hexapod_3.png</image>
				<text>
					To send controls to the bot a phone is used to set up a BLE connection to a nRF51822 module. The data is then sent for processing to the MCU.
				</text>
			</column>
		</element>
		<element>
			<name>NES Controller</name>
			<column>
				<text>
					This project was assigned for a class project in a digital logic design class. Some of the most notable learned lessons in this project relate to teamwork and the necessity of delegation between members. Together we were able to solve issues efficiently, quickly and most importantly have a thorough understanding of our solution.
				</text>
			</column>
			<column>
				<image>nes_1.png</image>
				<text>
					The project covered many different aspects but you can view the full write up for yourself here: 
				</text>
				<document>
					nesproject.pdf
				</document>
			</column>
		</element>
		<element>
			<name>Drones</name>
			<column>
				<image>drone_1.png</image>
				<image>drone_2.png</image>
				<image>drone_3.png</image>
				<image>drone_4.png</image>
				<image>drone_5.png</image>
			</column>
			<column>
				<text>
					Over the years I have grown an interest for flying and building multicopters. The goal has two parts, one to build a very fast flying machine but the second which is probably harder is to be able to control it. I have built around five different multicopters. At the Oregon State campus I am also part of a robotics club chapter dedicated to racing drones. So not only has this outlet provided me experience and knowledge but also many friendships.
				</text>
			</column>
		</element>
	</pages>
</data>